[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 16]
[Ministry of Justice]
You didn't sleep well, did you?
I told you to come home with me, but you wouldn't listen.
You said
you wanted to go to the History Archive to find clues.
I guess you not only didn't find any clues,
but you did manage to catch a cold.
Don't even mention it.
There's too much.
There're so many records.
Those people really know how to write.
They would record anything,
even the tiniest details.
You spent the whole night reading the files, right?
I couldn't sleep anyway.
I think
you should go back to Shen's Mansion first.
At worst,
you'll have to say a few nice words
to Grand Commander Shen.
Why should I?
I really think you should.
Yesterday, I
witnessed everything with my own eyes.
This time,
you might have really
misunderstood him a bit.
What did I misunderstand about him?
The day you were arrested,
Lai Luozhi arrived quickly.
Fortunately, Grand Commander Shen
also arrived in time.
You cleared your name so quickly
thanks to
Grand Commander Shen.
It's only been a few days,
yet there're already so many new sects
which claim that they know how to
bring the dead back
to life and achieve immortality.
We've already sent people to investigate thoroughly.
However,
most of them preach randomly,
mainly spreading heretical teachings.
It's difficult to track their next move.
Fire Moth Sect?
Of all sects,
the Fire Moth Sect
can be said to be the most dominant.
Moreover, there are rumors that
the core figure of the Fire Moth Sect
is Chen Huo'e, who was supposedly resurrected.
Mom.
Let's leave.
I haven't finished praying yet.
Xing, you...
Mom.
What are you doing here?
I came to pray for blessings for you and your father.
Don't believe everything you hear.
Let's go quickly.
Let's leave right away.
No, no, it's about to...
-It’ll work soon.
-Let’s go.
What's going on here?
Attention, everyone.
You are not allowed to gather here without reason.
Disperse immediately.
Why should we leave?
We haven't done anything wrong.
Those who obstruct the Fire Moth Sect
will be punished by gods.
Arrest them all.
You people
will be punished by gods!
You will be punished by gods!
Let go of me!
Let's go.
Mother.
What were you doing there?
It was so dangerous.
Keep your voice down.
I was just
praying for blessings for you and your father,
so that you may live a long life,
and be free from disasters and difficulties.
That's all a scam.
Throw that away...
No, no, I can't.
If I do, I'll be punished by gods.
This is a holy object of the Fire Moth Sect.
It's an incarnation of the gods.
It must not be violated.
All those who are disrespectful to the Fire Moth gods
will be hanged,
tied up in the shape of a moth,
-and be punished with fire.
-Mother.
Where did you hear all this?
Come on.
Even the children on the street know
that those offending the Fire Moth Sect
will end up being burned alive.
I can't believe this thing
has already bewitched so many people.
I must investigate this thoroughly.
Mother.
If you continue to get involved with those things,
you'll be in great danger.
Listen to me.
Stay at home.
And don't go anywhere for now.
I'll take this away.
No.
Give it back to me.
You ungrateful daughter, give it back to me.
You little troublemaker.
Then, don't be disrespectful.
And don't offend the Fire Moth Sect.
[History Archive]
It's so hot.
There's a fire!
The History Archive is on fire!
-Fire!
[History Archive]
Hurry!
Quickly, bring water!
[History Archive]
Get water here fast!
Coming, coming!
[History Archive]
Go get water quickly!
Hurry up!
Get water!
This way, this way!
Coming, coming! Hurry!
[History Archive]
Over here, over here!
Go again, go again!
Xing...
Xing!
Quick!
Bring water!
Shen Du!
Shen Du.
♫Who will save me from my loneliness and confusion?♫
♫Understanding my fragility, no words are needed♫
♫Who will save me from my panic and obsession?♫
♫Sheltering my solitude, never letting me fall♫
♫The chains of fate between us cannot be broken♫
♫Holding the warmth you once gave♫
♫Guiding me to see myself, the person I truly am♫
♫Who will save me from right and wrong?♫
♫Tossed in the sea of people, just hold me tight♫
♫Who will save me from grudges and karma?♫
♫Healing my sorrow, never letting me escape♫
♫The past fades, how many times have we met?♫
♫Who can break free from destiny?♫
♫I'll cross rivers and leap into fire for you♫
Xing.
♫I'm willing to disappear with you in the hustle and bustle♫
You're awake.
You inhaled a lot of smoke.
You need to have a good rest.
I'm sorry.
And thank you for saving me.
Get some rest.
Don't talk too much.
Sometimes when I speak,
I can be quite blunt.
If I said something offensive,
please don't take it to heart.
I understand.
Do you think
the fire was set by someone deliberately?
Was it to destroy
the county records and files inside?
Or it was meant to kill you.
To kill me?
Are they afraid I'll find out the truth?
I doubt we could find another person
as bold as you.
What are you doing?
I got this powder on my coat when saving you.
What exactly is it?
Perhaps only my master
knows what this is.
Be careful.
What's wrong?
Are you feeling unwell?
No.
I-I-I'm fine.
Now you know
how dangerous it is out there.
Get some rest.
Don't go anywhere.
[Jingshen Pavilion]
Master.
Just to have some tea,
why do we have to come
so far away here?
It's only here
that you can taste the flavor you want.
Don't believe me? Try it yourself.
[Jingshen Pavilion]
That's not the right way to drink tea.
You're drinking too fast.
Master.
This is the powder found on the crime scene.
It was also found
near the original site of the Jinxiu Workshop.
But we don't know where it was from.
[Jingshen Pavilion]
Don't smell it.
Interesting.
It's flammable.
And it burns without leaving a trace.
This doesn't seem like something an ordinary sorcerer would use
for their cultivation.
I'm afraid it might be
something that came from foreign tribes.
From foreign tribes?
Perhaps someone in the Ghost Market
might know
the origin of this thing.
Master.
It's such a shame that you no longer solve cases
with your skills
[Jingshen Pavilion]
Well, you've already learned
most of my skills.
Looks like
it's time for me to retire.
At my age,
I value peace and quiet.
I just seize every day
and enjoy my life.
Now I can leisurely enjoy tea every day,
[Jingshen Pavilion]
feeling carefree.
I feel quite content with my life.
It's hot!
You...
You can't drink hot tea when you're hasty.
The same principle applies to solving cases.
When you're too eager for results,
you'll be misled
by what you see
on the surface.
Misled by what I saw on the surface.
Yes, Master.
The evidences I have now
seem to have been
left there
deliberately.
Investigating a case
is not just about uncovering the truth.
[Jingshen Pavilion]
It's like a contest between you
and your unknown enemies.
It is to see who will
control the situation faster.
If back then,
the Jinxiu Workshop case
was to weaken Princess Runing's power,
damaging the relationship between Grand Empress Dowager and the Princess
as well as the noble Xiao family
behind the Princess,
then this time,
what's the purpose of those behind the scenes?
It's still unclear.
Don't rush.
Solving cases is like tasting tea.
It takes time and effort.
Sounds like everything is like tasting tea.
[Jingshen Pavilion]
That's right.
Marriage is also the same.
Master.
I'm talking about the case.
I'm not talking about anything else.
When drinking wine, heroes talk about everything.
When enjoying tea, people can talk about love.
The tea
gets more flavorful with each sip.
People are the same.
Time reveals a person's true nature.
Good tea.
Good tea indeed.
[Wise and Insightful]
Xing, wait.
Come with me.
Didn't I tell you
to rest in the mansion?
The bad old guy Wu Taiming
is worried you might be unlucky and bring bad luck here.
So he doesn't want you here.
It's all because of me.
Was Ji Fangming implicated
and scolded?
He was the one who guarded the History Archive.
The archive was almost burned down.
Wu Taiming
didn't dare to be angry with you.
So Ji Fangming
got scolded a lot.
I should think about
how to apologize to him.
By the way,
I heard that
you were carried out
by Grand Commander Shen in front of everyone.
So what?
He couldn't have just stood by and watched me die.
You
are like a cooked duck.
So stubborn.
You
just blurt out everything.
You have no filter.
Look at yourself.
You've only been back at the mansion for one day,
and now you look radiant.
Let me see.
What magic does Shen's Mansion
have?
It makes your eyes so bright and lively.
But...
You know what,
when I went back last night,
I fell asleep as soon as I lay down.
Could it be that
I've gotten used to sleeping with lights on
because I've adapted to the Shen mansion's all-night illumination?
On the contrary, here,
I couldn't sleep.
Alright.
I'm serious.
[Shen's Mansion]
What are these?
You saved my life.
To repay you,
I've specially prepared
some dishes that will help
with the recovery of your eyes.
From today on,
the nourishing meals for you
will always be offered by me
until your eyes
are fully healed.
Why don't you start eating?
Do you
not like the food?
Or you don't feel like eating?
These dishes
were made with sincerity by me.
Don't waste them.
I'll take my leave now.
♫With a gaze, I know our destiny♫
♫When we meet again, I know you're my Mr. Right♫
♫The stars remind me of our past♫
♫Our love started to grow long ago♫
What's the hurry?
♫Don't ask about the thoughts of the lover by the candlelight♫
♫Our love will last forever♫
Since when
have you developed this new bad habit?
♫With the gentle night breeze, I tell you how much I love you♫
Why do you need someone to keep you company while eating now?
♫Now I have someone to cherish in my life♫
Didn't you make these for me?
When I watch you,
♫I love you so much and you're my true love♫
the food taste even better.
♫With the moon in autumn and the breeze in spring, you're my only true love♫
♫Your palms and your eyes♫
I told you
♫Our love is getting stronger and stronger♫
not to be in a hurry.
♫I love you so much and you're my true love♫
You're a grown man now.
Don't tell me
you need someone to feed you.
♫With the moon in autumn and the breeze in spring, you're my only true love♫
♫Your palms and your eyes♫
♫Our love is getting stronger and stronger♫
♫You're my only true love♫
This meal is truly made with love.
Honey.
Let's start eating.
From now on,
remember to dine with me for every meal.
Will you agree or not?
I'm living in your house.
Do I have a choice?
Good that you know this.
What's wrong?
You're eating so messily.
I am not.
I'm not.
What's this about?
They're in perfect harmony.
What a lovely loving couple.
They're so attached to each other.
They really are.
But I don't know
how long this will last.
Go to the one who really harmed you.
Don't come to me.
It wasn't me, it wasn't me.
Don't come to me, don't come to me.
Don't come to me. Don't come to me.
Don't come to me.
[Bright and Virtuous]
Grand Commander.
When we arrived,
the person was already tied to the eaves.
I didn't dare to change anything of the scene
so I waited for you to take further action.
Grand Commander.
Chen Shoujie is not dead yet.
Fortunately, the people sent to watch him
rescued him in time.
However,
he seems to have suffered quite a shock.
He was already mentally unstable,
and now
he can't even say
a complete sentence anymore.
The scene here is like
what happened at the Furong Garden back then.
At that time, Han Shiyuan and Sister Caiwei
were also tied up and hung high.
There was burning charcoal below.
But back then, what was burning
was the Cold Flame used in the Western Regions' acrobatics.
Looks like
they really meant to kill him.
Who on earth
intended to kill Chen Shoujie
in such a cruel way?
Let's go.
How come Chen's mansion was burned down like this?
It's terrible.
Who's there?
Why are you hiding?
Jing Lin.
What's going on here?
What's happening?
They've caught someone.
It's you.
He
is from the Ministry of Justice.
He's Ji Fangming, who guarded the History Archive.
Regarding the fire at the History Archive,
we still need your statement and signature.
On my way to Shen's Mansion,
I saw you
hurrying here.
Grand Commander.
Someone was burned to death in the east of the city.
What?
Burned to death?
Who was it?
It was a guard from our Imperial Security Bureau,
Captain Sun.
It's him.
Do you know about the Fire Moth Sect?
The Fire Moth Sect?
It was Chen Huo'e
who punished him in person.
You know what?
The other day, at the Ministry of Justice,
a sudden big fire broke out.
The fire was to
punish the Madam of Shen's Mansion.
The Madam of Shen's Mansion?
She almost burned to death.
Maybe it's because
White Ghost has done countless evil deeds
and the retribution has fallen upon his wife.
The sound of wind and rain came in the night.
I kept sitting still like a bell.
Stuffed from a late-night snack,
I still need a few more drinks.
Have you traced the origin
of the powder I asked you to investigate?
It is from the Western Regions.
It's quite mysterious.
It took me
quite some time and effort
to investigate it.
Trying to charge me more money?
No way.
Don't you know the code words?
How could you come and bring nothing for me?
At the very least,
you should bring a couple of jugs of wine
to reward me.
If you admit
that you are the famous
folk detective Pan Chi,
I might consider
treating you to the best
osmanthus wine in the Xiang'an City.
I am!
If I really were,
will you
pay me
more money?
Dream on.
Thinking about it makes me feel nice.
You should go back too.
The Ghost Market hasn't been peaceful these days.
Grand Commander.
I've got new information of Ji Fangming from the Ministry of Justice,
the person you asked me to investigate.
I got a prescription
written by him
for himself.
He's with disease?
I didn't expect him
to know about pharmacology.
After following him for a few days,
I found that his health
was indeed not very good.
It seems to be a chronic illness.
[Two taels of Danshen, two taels of Baizhi, four taels of sandalwood, two taels of Peilan]
Give this prescription to the pharmacy.
I want to see
what illness he's actually suffering from.
You suspect him?
The fire at the History Archive of the Ministry of Justice
was set at too convenient a time.
Grand Commander must be busy.
I just came to ask
what kind of tea he would like.
Don't bother.
Miss Yun Que, please go back.
Is there any progress
on the Jinxiu Workshop case?
Don't worry, Miss.
When necessary,
Grand Commander will surely inform you.
I've found something.
The powder
was made from a plant unique to the Western Regions,
It was made by grinding the plant.
When burned,
it produces a special odor
that can make those who smell it
feel extremely excited,
or even hallucinate.
It's said that
if someone misleads
those who smell it in secret,
they will
have the same
hallucinations.
In the Ghost Market,
is someone selling the powder?
Actually, no.
It's said that although this plant
is common in the Western Regions,
once it is taken out
of the specific soil,
it's hard for it to survive.
So this powder
cannot be stored
for too long
if they are to have
a strong hallucinogenic effect.
Could it be that
someone has secretly cultivated
this plant in the capital?
Is your information reliable?
I got it from my friend Pan Chi
in the Ghost Market.
The information from him is never wrong.
Do you know that Ji Fangming is sick?
You only rely on your friend from the Ghost Market,
ignoring the clues right in front of you.
That time at Chen Shoujie's mansion,
his reaction and the timing of his arrival
were both very strange.
Others were interested in
what had happened inside the room,
but he was curious about
our reactions to seeing these things.
That's right.
I also remember
I once smelled a faint scent
on Ji Fangming.
I didn't pay much attention to it at the time,
but now I feel
that scent is somewhat familiar,
but not common.
I've only smelled it in one place before.
At the Mingsheng Temple.
He's been to the Mingsheng Temple?
I asked Chuichui
to investigate Ji Fangming's background.
While at it, I also inquired
about his personal information.
His entry into the Ministry of Justice
was through someone's recommendation.
Guess who recommended him?
Could it be...
That's right.
It was Chen Shoujie.
Apart from this,
there's nothing special about his past.
Nothing suspicious was found.
The more ordinary it looks, the more suspicious it is.
There must be some hidden truth behind it.
Chen Shoujie in the past
once kindly recommended him.
But that day at the crime scene,
he pretended not to know him.
Chen Shoujie recommended him?
I've investigated both of them.
They seem to have had no connection at all.
That means
apart from them two,
there must be someone we haven't discovered
who is linked to
both of them.
It seems
we'll have to question them personally.
Mr. Ji.
Here.
Miss Yan.
These are?
Finally, we don't have to look at those
incomplete records anymore.
You mean
you've found the culprit?
Yes, we have.
All these crimes
were committed by Chen Shoujie.
He was pretending to be a lunatic
deceiving everyone.
In fact,
he was just talking to himself all along.
What?
He pleaded guilty?
Yes.
You know how good my husband is.
He's the well-known White Ghost.
In less than a day,
Chen Shoujie confessed to everything.
He was just pretending to be crazy.
How could this be possible?
Why wouldn't it be possible?
It was him.
He deliberately concealed
the key evidences of the Jinxiu Workshop case.
So many people died unjustly because of him.
He was bribed
with a thousand taels of gold,
which he buried in his own courtyard.
It took
several hours of digging
to unearth it.
I can't believe it.
I really can't believe
he hid everything so well.
Yes.
If my husband hadn't figure out everything,
we would still be deceived.
Is he now
detained in Imperial Security Bureau?
He's in the prison of the Ministry of Justice.
Tomorrow,
he'll be executed in secret.
Be executed in secret?
Why?
It's the decision from the above.
Perhaps,
there might be some hidden truths
behind this case.
If Princess Runing
was confined in Mingsheng Temple
because she was deliberately wronged,
then the Jinxiu Workshop case
might just be
made
to scheme against the royal princess.
What?
Are you saying
the dozen or so lives lost in the Jinxiu Workshop
were just for...
We can't speak of such things.
Therefore,
the investigation can't go any further.
It was all my fault.
Who ordered you to do it?
More a dozen lives at the Jinxiu Workshop were lost because of you!
Still pretending?
I'll kill you today.
It's fake.
Those who offend the Fire Moth Sect
will suffer the Fire Moth's punishment.
Ji Fangming.
It's really you.
You deliberately said those things
to lure me here.
You had many chances
to kill Chen Shoujie,
but you didn't.
We were speculating
that perhaps what the killer wanted
was not Chen Shoujie's death,
but to torture him.
No one wanted more than the killer
for him to be conscious.
That way, the torture
would be more satisfying.
Ji Fangming.
Now you're caught red-handed.
Do you have anything to say?
I am not the murderer.
I don't even know
why I'm here.
Perhaps I was bewitched by some bad guy
and came here in a state of confusion.
Grand Commander Shen, Mrs. Shen.
You've encountered
such situations before.
You should be able to understand, right?
I have absolutely no
reason to kill Chen Shoujie.
You did everything for the owner of the Jinxiu Workshop
Kong Xianrong, right?
It's been so many years.
Few dare to mention
the criminal of the Jinxiu Workshop treason case.
I never expected
that someone would still remember his name.
You set fire
to the Ministry of Justice's History Archive
It wasn't just to harm me.
What you wanted
was to destroy the documents there.
You wanted to erase all the evidences
of your connection with Chen Shoujie
and Kong Xianrong, the owner of the Jinxiu Workshop.
The three of you
had known each other for a long time.
Is this all you have,
Miss Yan?
Is it enough to convict me?
So you're admitting it?
I got to know Xianrong long ago.
The two of us had a lot in common.
We met while taking shelter from the rain in a teahouse.
[Kong Xianrong]
Xian Rong was eloquent and articulate.
He was very talented.
We hit it off immediately.
Our conversations were delightful.
[First-Place Scholar] [Second-Place Scholar]
We quickly became close friends.
After I failed the imperial examination,
[Jinxiu Workshop]
he introduced me
to Chen Shoujie
so that I got to work for the government.
However,
something unexpected happened.
The people of the Jinxiu Workshop were wrongly accused.
Kong Xianrong's entire family was executed.
I stood among the crowd,
watching his family die tragically.
Blood flowed like a river.
How do you know
that Kong Xianrong was wrongly accused?
Over these years,
I've read all the county records
and checked all the criminal case files.
Finally,
I found
vital clues.
Kong treated Chen Shoujie like a brother,
but Chen Shoujie,
for his own selfish desires,
betrayed Kong who trusted him so much.
So,
you killed his wife
and tried every means
to torment Chen Shoujie.
She deserved to die!
Chen deserved to die!
Chen Shoujie deserved to die even more.
Did you kill Captain Sun
who worked for the Imperial Security Bureau
in the east of the city?
His life or death
was not my concern.
Then who exactly
taught you to impersonate Chen Huo'e to commit the crime?
Moths to a flame.
Born at dawn, dead by dusk.
Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation.
Put Ji Fangming in prison.
Await further orders.
I was avenging the people of the Jinxiu Workshop
who were wrongly accused.
I did nothing wrong!
Chen Shoujie deserved to die, he deserved to die!
[Shen's Mansion]
Is the food not good today?
Why aren't you talking?
You were provoking Ji Fangming today.
It was completely reckless.
What if something had gone wrong...
Anyway, I made him confess.
Indeed,
simple methods
sometimes are more effective.
The rest
depends on
how you as the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau,
will conduct the court interrogation.
I'm afraid this case isn't that simple.
Ji Fangming has already been detained.
If evidence is found to convict him,
can we close the case then?
If everything
was done by Ji Fangming,
then closing the case
is the right thing to do.
But there's one thing
that doesn't feel right.
What doesn't feel right?
The Fire Moth Sect's attempt to make a god
is progressing faster
than we imagined.
When Ji Fangming
tried to burn Chen Shoujie to death,
they committed
a crime in the east of the city at the same time.
It can be said they acted without any fear.
The person
behind the Fire Moth Sect
is really
Chen Huo'e was resurrected?
Your cooking skills
have shown no improvement, I must say.
But after I ate food made by you many times,
I don't feel it's not that terrible.
My skills haven't improved,
but you can
have a better appetite.
The person you arrested
was seeking revenge for the people at the Jinxiu Workshop
I risked my life to collect
the evidences for the Jinxiu Workshop case.
If there's an interrogation,
I want to go along as well.
[Ministry of Justice]
Ji Fangming,
you murdered
Chen Shoujie's wife, Madam Chen.
While attempting to assassinate
Chen Shoujie,
you were caught red-handed.
Tell us the whole story,
and who else you collaborated with.
Confess truthfully.
Grand Commander Shen, that's quite an intimidating manner.
In all my years at the Ministry of Justice,
I've seen plenty of bluffing.
This tactic won't work on me.
Ji Fangming,
at this point, you'd better come clean.
Don't try these useless tricks.
If you won't confess here,
we'll take you to the Imperial Security Bureau.
I have plenty of methods at my disposal.
Grand Commander, are you going to force him
to confess by torturing him?
Lord Lai, you're right on time.
As they say, it's not about being early, but being timely.
If I hadn't come,
how could I see you
being so intimidating?
This case was assigned by the Grand Empress Dowager
to be handled solely by the Imperial Security Bureau.
I know what to do.
You just need to observe,
and don't cause any trouble.
Otherwise, you'll be charged with
disrupting the proceedings.